(走过的路)
我听到你的祈祷
I heard your prayer.
那个天使骗了我
The angel lied to me.
他不是他自称的那个人
He's not who he said he was.
他的名字是 Gadreel
His name,Gadreel.
Gadreel为Metatron卖命
Gadreel is working for Metatron.
Metatron让Gadreel杀了Kevin
Metatron made Gadreel kill Kevin.
我才是
I was the one who caused.
让所有天使都坠天的人
All the angels to fall.
他把我的荣光拿去施咒
He took my grace for the spell.
这么说你现在是凡人了
That means your human.
女王万岁
Long live the queen.
那是该隐之印
That's the bloody mark of Cain.
没有印记 初刃是无效的
Without the mark,the blade is useless.
你本该领导所有天使 Castiel
You're supposed to lead the angels,Castiel.
我只想让我的人回家
Just trying to get my people home.
你不是英雄
You are not the hero.
我才是
I'm the hero.
你不知道
You don't know.
当凡人的感觉
What is like to be human.
我慢慢觉得 初刃在
I'm starting to think the blade is doing something.
改变你
To you.
你有没有告诉他们 你的荣光是偷来的 Castiel
Have you told them about your stolen grace,Castiel.
惩罚他
Punish him.
我做不到
I can't.
你刚为了一个人放弃了整个天使军团
Cass you just gave up an entire army for one guy.
他使用的是天使预言石的能量
He's powering up with the angel tablet.
Metatron的神秘门
Metatron's secret portal.
从现在开始
From here on out.
我一个人说了算 明白了吗
I'm calling the shots,capisce.
我不是来挑事的
I'm not here to fight.
请至少给我一次机会
At least give me a chance
(如今)
放下初刃 Dean
Drop the blade,Dean.
让开
Move.
- Dean - Sam
- Dean - Sam.
让开
Move.
放下
Let it go.
放手
你们有什么权利阻止我
The hell if you think I'm riding the pine on this one guys.
Dean 你现在很不对劲
Look,something is wrong with you,Dean.
我们查清楚怎么回事之前
Until we figure out what.
你只能待在这里
This is where you have to stay.
然后你们能干什么
And you two are gonna do what.
就凭你们两个干掉Metatron吗
Take on Metatron yourselves.
真是 聪明啊
That's...smart.
等等 你 你的天使军队已经不跟你了
Oh no,wait,you,you lost your angel army.
你呢 你现在想把
And you,you're trying to lock up.
唯一能杀了那个混蛋的人
The one guy who has a shot.
给关起来
And kill that son of a bitch.
计划得挺不错啊
Hell of a plan,fellas.
听着 喂
Look,hey,guys.
Sam
Sam.
Sammy
Sammy.
- Sam - 怎么了
- Sam - Yeah.
Dean说的没错
Dean wasn't wrong.
我的人已经不跟我了
My followers have abandoned us.
是 但是Gadreel说他会帮我们
Yeah,and Gadreel says he can help us.
从我的角度看
From where I sit.
他的价值比天使军团更大
That's more than an even trade.
那个 Metatron
So...Metatron.
Metatron
Metatron.
上帝
God.
马上
Just a second.
你是在写新的天使指南吗
Is that the new angel handbook you're working on or.
不是
No no.
我在写一个故事 Neil
This is a story,Neil.
一个精妙绝伦的故事
A marvelous story.
充满了爱
Full of love and.
心碎
Heartbreak and.
- 还有爱 - 就像恋恋笔记本
- Love - Sort of like The Notebook.
我喜欢恋恋笔记本
I love The Notebook.
不
No.
快
Quick.
哪个让我看起来更可怜
Which makes me look more pathetic.
你为什么想看起来可怜
Why do you wanna look pathetic.
你不久前刚刚整合了所有天使
You just reunited all the angels under the banner of heaven.
- 就像是 - 获了人民选择奖一样吗
- I mean that's like - Winning a People's Choice Award.
不过还是不太一样 对吗
Not quite the real deal now,is it.
- 都好了吗 - 是的长官
- All set - Yes,sir.
打开开关
Flip the switch.
等亮了灯 一切就绪
Wait till the light and bingo.
所有天使 不管天上地下
And every angel in heaven and on earth.
都能听到我吗
Will hear me.
是的 只能听到您
You and only you.
信号阻断了天使电台其他的声音
The signal blocks out all other voices on angel radio.
来吧
Come on.
请注意
Hello.
我是Metatron
This is Metatron.
我增强了混音效果
More reverb.
你以为我是Lou Gehrig吗
Because I'm Lou Gehrig.
抱歉抱歉
Sorry,sorry.
别再做那个手势了
Don't do that.
我想在此刻对大家表示 欢迎回来
I'd like to take a moment to welcome you all back.
我想让你们知道
I want you to know.
你们接受我成为你们的新上帝
How moved I am that you accepted me.
我有多么感动
As your new god.
我的心 可以说 是满满的
My heart,as they say,is full.
所以我想跟大家分享一些好消息
Which is why I want to share some wonderful news with you.
我要去小小的旅行一下
I'm going on a short trip.
天堂的大门会暂时关闭
Heaven's door will be temporarily closed.
直到我再次归来 但是不用担心
Pending my return but rest assured.
一切都会解释清楚
All will be explained.
而且将会
And it will be.
无上光荣
Glorious.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going.
去把剩下的故事讲完啊
To tell the rest of the story.
求你了
Please.
我不会再找你们麻烦 我发誓
I'll leave you alone,I swear.
我们不是来伤害你的
We're not here to hurt you.
不 你的荣光
No,your grace.
治愈我只会让你更衰弱
Healing me will only weaken you.
你听到他了吗
Did you hear him.
Metatron吗 听到了
Metatron,yes.
他要去哪儿 他到底要什么
Where is he going?What does he want.
恐怕是 全人类
I'm afraid,humanity.
哦 上帝啊
Oh,god.
我以为在打败Abaddon以后
I would have thought you'd be more relaxed.
你会更轻松呢
Having defeated Abaddon.
怎么说呢
What can I say.
我就是个爱操心的命
I wear my stress.
你知道
You know.
现在有这么多恶魔重新归顺于你
With so many demons having railed back to your side.
他们最应该做的就是 找到他们的
It's only natural that they would look to their.
王
King.
请求复命
For some...direction.
亲爱的 如果我想让Phil医生帮我做精油按摩
Love,if I wanted a soapy massage from Dr.Phil.
我会播快捷号码3的 好吗
I would hit three on the speed dial,all right.
对不起 先生
I'm sorry,sir.
先生 我觉得您被召唤了
Sir,I believe you being summoned.
还是个Winchester
It's a Winchester.
那是什么味道
What's that smell.
我到底怎么了 你个狗娘养的
What the hell is happening to me,you son of a bitch.
喝高了 吃坏肚子了 我怎么知道
Liquor before beer,bad taco,how should I know.
我停不下来
I can't turned it off.
自从我杀了Abaddon
Ever since I killed Abaddon.
就好像被什么 困住了一样
It's like this whole...other thing.
我很亢奋 我需要杀人
I get this high and I...I need to kill.
我真的真的很想杀人
I mean I really really need to kill.
如果我不这么做
And if I don't.
你就想把五脏六腑都吐出来
You yak your guts out.
是该隐之印
It's the mark.
什么意思
Meaning.
它会引诱你大开杀戒
It wants you to kill.
你杀的越多 感觉越好
The more you kill the better you feel.
杀的越少 感觉越糟糕
The less kill the less better you feel.
能有多糟糕
How much less better.
能想到的最糟糕的情况呗
One would imagine the least best better.
就是说 死
So,dead.
该隐也有那个印记 但他没有死
Well,Cain had the mark,he didn't die.
该隐是个恶魔
Cain was a demon.
你的身体不够强大
Your body is not strong enough.
容纳不了初刃的力量
To contain the blade's power.
如果我摆脱掉它呢
What if I get rid of it.
你想摆脱掉它吗
You wanna get rid of it.
我想杀Metatron
What I want is Metatron.
说下去
Go on.
但我必须要先走出这扇门
But I have to get to that door.
必须拿到初刃
And I have to get to the blade.
你得帮我
And you're gonna help me.
不
Oh no.
什么味道
What's that smell.
硫磺
Sulfur.
Dean 赶快给我回电话
Dean,pick up the phone,call me back.
我没有开玩笑 好吗
I'm not kidding,all right.
不要这样做 千万别这样
Don't do this,not like this.
你确定是Crowley吗
Are you sure it was Crowley.
除了他还有谁
Who else would he summon.
自从Dean得到那个印记
I mean he and Crowley have been.
他跟Crowley动不动就厮混在一起
Bromancing over the blade ever since Dean got the mark.
什么印记
The mark.
该隐之印
The mark of Cain.
Dean就是用那东西砍我的是吗
So that's what Dean cut me with.
初刃
The First Blade.
那东西可能有用
In a way that could be useful.
什么意思
What.
虽然Metatron变得比以前更强大了
Well,Metatron is more powerful than ever.
但如果Dean有初刃和该隐之印
But if Dean has the First Blade and the mark.
那他可能是我们最大的希望了
That might give us our best chance.
你在开玩笑 是吗
You're joking,right.
一个小时前我们才把Dean监禁起来
An hour ago we're ready to throw Dean to a padded cell.
但现在你却说 他是我们的杀手锏
And now you say he's our best chance.
听他说完 Sam
Hear him out,Sam.
好吧 不好意思 对不住了各位
Oh right,excuse me,sorry guys.
抱歉 可我不是很想听到
Sorry I'm a little less than eager to hear.
我们最有力的条件是对准弹头发射
That our best chance is arming the warhead.
希望能一击致命
And hoping it hits the mark.
我们不是在讨论一颗炸弹
This is not a bomb we are talking about.
我们在说我亲哥
This is my brother.
你的亲兄弟不会是一个人在战斗
And your brother would not be in this alone.
我们会协助他
We can help.
怎么协助
How.
我知道Metatron已经发现了
I belive Metatron has found a way.
接入天使预言石的方法
To tap into the angel tablet.
这样一来 他所汇集的能量近乎于
Harnessing its power to give him powers equivalent to.
上帝 对吗
God,right.
其实从头到尾他的目的就只有这一个
I mean that's what this is all about,isn't it.
Metatron想成为上帝
Metatron wants to be God.
好极了 这下他无人能敌了
Great,well that basically makes him unstoppable.
只要我们能切断
Not if we can break the connection.
Metatron和预言石之间的连接
Between Metatron and the tablet.
就能把他打回原形
That would make him just an ordinary angel.
预言石在哪儿
Where's the tablet.
在Metatron的办公室里
Metatron's office.
天堂里吗
In heaven.
我能带你们去神秘门
I can get us to the door.
然后呢
And then what.
难道打开大门欢迎您吗
I mean why would they let you in.
如果Metatron的二把手与天堂头号通缉犯联手
If Metatron's number two shows up with heavon's most wanted.
基本就没戏了
The gig is up.
Sam 我们必须搏一把
Sam we have to try.
该死的 Al
Damn it Al.
我不管你今晚有什么安排
I don't care what you got going on tonight.
他也是你儿子
He's your kid,too.
我跟你说过了 他在吸毒
And I'm telling you he's on drug.
上帝啊 天哪
Oh my God Oh my God.
她死了
She's dead,man.
She's dead.
我可不这么认为
I'm not so sure about that.
两位要来点什么
What can I get you fellas.
黑咖啡
Coffee,black.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you serious.
你坐人家的桌子 占用人家的时间
You take this girl's table,her time.
像过度发育的未成年一样往这儿一坐
You spread out like an overgrown teenager.
为了什么
For what.
一杯咖啡才多少小费 5分有吗
What was the tip a single cup of Joe,a nickle.
双层芝士汉堡
Double cheese burger.
加全料 多加洋葱
Everything,heavy on the onions.
马上
You got it.
所以你和麋鹿平时就干些这个 对吧
So this is what you and moose do, eh?
在全国各地来回穿梭 搜寻邪恶势力
Crisscross the country,searching for evil.
正餐吃化肥
Order your nitrates.
同时游览当地风光
Partake of the local attraction.
对
Yep.
你们从来不会厌烦这种鬼日子吗
You never get tired of the rat race.
从来没想过某天
Never get the urge to just.
撒手不干
Bugger off.
对月长啸吗
And howl at the moon.
从来不会问自己生活的意义吗
Never ask yourself,is this it.
这就是人生的全部了吗
Is this all there is.
我喝过人血 你了解的
I kicked human blood,you know.
哦 所以你现在又要开始哭哭啼啼了啊
Oh,so you are full metal douche again.
那敢情好
Well that's fantastic.
要给你拿只泰迪熊吗
Would you like a stuffed bear.
只是想和你聊聊天
Just trying to make conversation.
地狱怎么样 Crowley
How's hell,Crowley.
地狱挺好的
Hell's fine.
地狱就像一块瑞士表
Hell's like a Swiss watch.
不用你愁
Don't worry about hell.
地狱的事一言难尽
Hell's complicated.
权利游戏也一言难尽
Game of Thrones complicated.
浴室性爱也不是一句能说清楚的
Shower sex is complicated.
地狱三言两语可尽
Hell ain't complicated.
你的问题不在地狱
Your problem ain't hell.
- 在于你自己 - 好吧
- It's you - Fair enough.
那你的麻烦又是什么
What's your problem then.
Metatron是我的大麻烦
My problem is Metatron.
目前无迹可寻
And right now there's nothing.
不见天使互相残杀
There's no angel smitings.
没有上帝的神迹
No crazy acts of God.
也没有虫灾 冰雹
No vermin,hail.
如果Metatron真的打算在人间作祟
If Metatron's making his move on earth.
他可真够有耐心的
He's taking his sweet ass time.
莫恐慌 是我的骑士们
Never fear,calvary's here.
然后呢
And.
显然 你要找的天使一下子火了
Apparently your angel has gone viral.
美国真是个好地方
And that America is perfaction.
喂哥 那可是你妹妹
Yo,dude that's your sister.
上帝啊
Oh my God.
她死了 死了
She's dead man,she's dead.
我可不这么认为
I'm not so sure about that.
他 他在搞什么
Is he...Is he freaking serious.
你看见了吗
Did you see that.
天啊
Holy.
你确定录下来了吗
Tell me you just got that.
伙计 你叫什么
Dude what's you name.
我叫Marv
Marv.
什么时候拍的
When was this taken.
2小时前 在印第安纳州的曼西
A Couple of hours ago in Muncie,Indiana.
他对她说了什么悄悄话
What did he whisper in her ear.
问得好
Exactly.
你不吃了吗
You are not gonna eat your food.
不饿
Not hungry.
通往天堂的门在儿童游乐区里吗
The door to heaven is in playground.
由Metatron的两位心腹看守
Guarded by two of Metatron's most loyal.
是我亲自挑选的
I recruited them myself.
你之前说你有计划
So you said you had a plan.
我们怎样说服他们 放我们进去
How we might convince them to let us pass.
伍基人
Wookiee.
我完全不明白你在说什么 兄弟
Brother,I have no idea what that means.
一部很受欢迎的电影里的梗
It's a reference to a very popular film.
算了
Never mind.
Asariel
Asariel.
Asariel Purah 把门打开
Asariel,Purah,make way.
门已经关上了 Gadreel
The door is closed,Gadreel.
Metatron下令关上的
By an order of Metatron.
你们以为是谁下命令去抓Castiel的
And who do you think give the order to capture Castiel.
除非你们觉得Metatron对于拷问
Unless you don't think Metatron isn't interested.
反叛军的首领完全没有兴趣
In questioning the leader of the rebellion.
我们必须得重新画一次咒语
The spell must be redrawn.
越快越好
As quickly as possible then.
交给我
I got this.
看来我们之中还有人
I guess one of us doesn't need a demon.
不需要靠恶魔来发现线索
To help follow a clue trail.
你在找那个被奇迹治愈的姑娘 对吧
You are looking for Miracle Lady,right.
她走了
Yeah,she is gone.
走之前我和她谈了谈
I had a nice chat with her though.
Sammy 无论你觉得你的介入起什么作用
Sammy,whatever kind of intervention you think this is.
相信我 都不是你想的那样
Trust me,it ain't.
我不会再解释给你听了
I am not gonna explain myself to you.
是啊 我明白
Yeah,I sort of get that.
只是觉得你可能想知道
I just thought you might want to know that.
就在你们俩在这扮演天生冤家的时候
While you two have been playing Odd Couple.
你真正的朋友们 比如Cass
You real friends,like Cass.
还有Gadreel 你捅了一刀的天使
Like the angel you stabbed,Gadreel.
他们正在努力拼命
They are out there right now.
帮你赢得这次战争
Risking their asses to help you win this fight.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about.
这场战争
A fight I might add.
本来可以简单直接许多
You made that much more complicated.
而你却捅了那个天使
When you decided to stab the one angel.
那个可以直接带我们去找Metatron的天使
Who could actually get us to Metatron.
你是指那个附过你身的天使吗
You mean the angel that took you for a joy ride.
是那个害死了Kevin的天使吗
The angel that slaughtered Kevin,that angel.
最初 是你让他进来的
Who you let in the front door in the first place.
是你欺骗了我 Dean
You tricked me,Dean.
如今是我
Now I'm the one.
常常在半夜被噩梦惊醒
That is to wake up in the middle of the night.
看到是我自己亲手杀害了Kevin 不是你
Seeing my hands killing Kevin,not you.
所以拜托你
So please.
你说你不想给我解释
When you say you don't want to explain anything to me.
那就闭嘴吧
Don't.
我懂了
I get it.
我也明白
And I also get.
Metatron必须要除掉
That Metatron has to go.
我知道你是我们最大的希望
And I know you are our best shot to do that.
我这次孤注一掷
I'm gonna take my shot.
无论结果是好是坏
For better or worse.
我知道
I know.
不论最后是生是死
No matter the consequences.
我明白
I know.
但是如果这是最后一次
But if this is it.
我们一起来
We are gonna do it together.
你想知道他在她耳边说了什么 对吧
You wanna know what he whispered to her right.
那段视频里
In the video.
是他的下一个目的地
His next stop.
你们到底在磨叽什么
So what are we all gollywagging on about.
快上车出发
Chop chop.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我可不是你们的三号恶魔小弟
I'm not exactly demon minion No.3 here.
正如传说 我可是有法术在身的
As the kids say I've got mad skills.
我不知道你到底在期待什么
I don't know what you expected here,okay.
我也不关心
I don't really care.
但是你要想现在退出
But you wanted off the hamster wheel.
那就退
Get off.
看来我已经被Winchester同化了
Guess I've been Winchestered.
祝你们好运
I wish you boys good luck.
如果这么说管用的话
If I thought it would help.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我们已经告诉Metatron了
We sent words to Metatron.
他很快就会回来
He will be back shortly.
你可以在里面等他
You can wait inside.
谢谢你 Ingrid
Thank you,Ingrid.
怎么回事
What's going on.
不 不 不要
No,no,no,not here.
你真的以为你的小伎俩能骗得过我们吗
Did you really think you little ruse would work.
求你了 不要
Please,please.
欢迎来到天堂监狱 Castiel
Welcome to the heaven jail,Castiel.
我相信Gadreel很乐意给你作介绍
I believe Gadreel can give you the tour.
请问
Excuse me.
抱歉打扰了 请问你是Marv吗
I'm sorry,but are you Marv.
这是我的朋友 George
This is my friend,George.
我听说 你创造了奇迹
I hear you perfor miracles.
我确实有这个能力
It is a burden I accept.
能施舍点儿麦芽酒给我吗
A little single malt.
- George - 怎么了
- George - What.
先把你的糖尿病治好怎么样
How about we take care of that diabetes.
我在你水壶里留了点儿小惊喜
Left you a little something to celebrate with.
谢谢
Thank you.
他是个骗子
He's a fraud.
我不明白你什么意思 先生
I'm afraid I don't know what you mean,good sir.
一个什么好处也不给的的人怎么会是骗子
How could one be a fraud when one offers nothing.
一点点爱 一点点希望
A little love,a little hope.
偶尔来点奇迹 没别的
The occasional miracle,nothing more.
你知道我什么意思 Metatron
You know exactly what I mean,Metatron.
你说什么
Excuse me.
他叫Metatron
His name is Metatron.
虽然他极力掩饰
And much as he'd like you to think.
但他跟你们不是同类人
He's not one of you.
他是天使
He's an angel.
我和他都是
We both are.
天使
An angle.
好吧
Okay.
我知道是谁在偷喝George的酒了
Somebody's been drinking out of George's canteen.
你不承认你以前是上帝的抄录员
So you deny you are the former scribe of God.
先生
Sir.
一个既惹人厌又失宠的小气天使
A petty,unliked,unloved angel.
这些人们不想听
These people don't want to hear.
他一味追求权利
Driven by the relentless pursuit of power.
没有别的
And nothing more.
这扯得太远了
This is really gone too far.
他用非常手段把剩余的天使
Who's already brought the rest of the angels.
招揽到他的强权之下
Under his iron thumb.
如果你不停下来 我就不客气了
As I will you brother,if you don't.
闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
上帝的抄录员天使 得了吧
Angel scribe of God,please.
这是真的
It's true.
我亲眼所见的才是真实的
What is true is what I can see with my own two eyes.
你要说他是个可怜又平凡的人
You wanna call him pathetic,common.
请随意
Be my guest.
这儿有谁不是吗
Who here isn't.
但是谁有这个人的天赋
But who here has the gift that this man has.
你知道他做了什么吗
Do you know what he did.
我想如果你看到了我所看到的
And I'm afraid if you've seen what I've seen.
你只会憎恶他
You'd think him as nothing more than an abomination.
憎恶
Abomination.
他是制造奇迹的人
Try miracle worker.
或者救世主
Try Messiah.
这个更好
Better.
对不起
I am sorry.
你们不相信我
You don't believe me.
但是我必须完成我的使命
But I must do what my mission demands.
我必须保护你们
I must protect you.
行不通的
Yeah,that's not gonna work.
他们爱我
They love me.
非常非常爱我
They really,really love me.
帮你一把
Little help.
发现什么了吗
Anything.
恩 他就在上面
Yeah,he's up there.
就在一英里之外
About a mile up theroad.
有个流浪汉营地
There's a homeless encampment.
听起来 那些人已经相信
The way the folks're talking,he's got them convinced.
他是什么新耶稣之类的人物了
He's some kinda new Jesus or something.
你还好吗
You good.
很好
Yeah,I'm good.
听着 Sammy
Listen,Sammy.
关于 过去这几个月
About the,you know,the last couple of months.
我明白
I know.
在我们去砍人之前
So,before we find something else to fight about.
告诉我 你准备好把他大卸八块了吗
Tell me,are you ready to gut this bitch.
对不起 兄弟
Sorry,little brother.
这不是你的战斗
It’s not your fight.
照你说 是Metatron陷害了你
Okay,so you're telling me that Metatron set you up.
他安排了那些天使去自爆
Arrange those suicide bombers.
让自己看起来像个受害者
To make himself look like the victim.
Gadreel是他的二把手
Gadreel is his second in command.
除了真相 还有什么
For what other reason than the truth.
能让他反抗Metatron
Would he turn against Metatron.
所以我现在就应该相信你和一个
So now I'm expected to trust the word of an angel.
自从伊甸园事件之后就一直
Who's only ever thought of himself.
只顾着自己的天使吗
Since the Garden and you.
你说过
You told us.
不会再有天使因战争而死了
Not a single angel more would die in this fight.
你觉得我一直这么拼命是在干什么
What do you think I have been trying to do.
拼命 拼命杀了Metatron吗
Trying?By killing Metatron.
他是我们所有痛苦的根源
He is the reason for all of our suffering.
你说什么都不重要
Nothing you say matters.
难道你想让我坐以待毙
Would you rather I not try at all.
除非你能证明
Not if you can prove it.
那就请给我们一个机会
So give us a chance.
放我们出去 Hannah
Let us out,Hannah.
求你了
Please.
我有什么能帮你的
May I help you.
放松点 首领
Take it easy,chief.
你是Dean Winchester
You are Dean Winchester.
你怎么知道的
And how do you know that.
他说你会来
He said you would coming.
好吧 我来了
Well,here I am.
Metatron在哪里
Where is Metatron.
是Marv
Marv.
好吧
Sure.
在那里面
In there.
为宽恕我们而祈祷
Praying for our forgivness.
宽恕什么
Forgivenss for what.
原来如此
Is he,now.
我在这监牢里
I sat in this hole.
苦等几千年
For thousands of years.
只为补偿自己的罪孽
Thinking about nothing but redemption.
然后恢复自己的信誉
Of reclaiming my good name.
无关他人 这一切都是我自己犯下的错
I thought of nobody,no cause other than my own.
你已经洗刷罪孽了 我的朋友
You've been redeemed,my friend.
最后唯一重要的只有使命
The only thing that matters in the end is the mission.
保护那些不会
Protecting those who would not.
且不能够保护自己的人
And can not protect themselves.
人类
The humans.
我们之中没有任何人比使命更重要
None of us is bigger than that.
我们不能让我们自身的恐惧
We will not let our fears.
和狂妄自大
Our self-absorption.
阻止我们去发现真相
Prevent of us seeing it through.
不能再这样下去了
Not anymore.
不 当然不能
No,of course not.
去监狱的另外一边 Castiel
Move to the other side of your cell,Castiel.
别抬头
And keep your head down.
你要干什么
What you are doing.
当他们提起我的名字时
When they say my name.
或许我将不再
Perhaps I won't.
不要
Don't.
只是那个将蛇放入园中的罪人
Just be the one who let the serpent in.
或许我会被称为
Pherhaps I will be known as one of the many.
Gadreel
Gadreel.
重建天堂的英雄之一
Who gave the heaven the second chance.
快跑吧 姐妹
Run,sister.
Gadreel
Gadreel.
你现在相信他了吧
Do you believe him now.
你这套忍辱负重的耶稣把戏
You can save the humble-pie Jessus routine.
在我面前就省省吧
For somebody who gives a damn.
Dean 你最大的毛病就是太愤世嫉俗
The problem with you,Dean,is the cynicism.
一直都如此
Always with the cynicism.
就算是最卑微不堪
Well,most people.
生活在肮脏底层的人
Even the real belly crawlers living in filth.
像是布伦特伍德这样的地方
Or Brentwood.
他们都不愿如此愤世
They do not want to be cynical.
他们只想要一个信仰
They just want to something to believe in.
你是说你吗
And that'd be you.
为什么不能是我
Why not me.
你只不过拉拢外面那些人们多久
You've been working those people outside for.
一天时间
What,a day.
他们就已经为你抛头颅撒热血
They've already spilled blood in your name.
而你不过是个长翅膀的诈骗犯
You are nothing but Bernie Madoff with wings.
所以我是个冒牌货
So I am a fake.
你到底明不明白
Do you have any idea.
你知道需要多少粉饰和美化
How much pancake make-up and soft lighting it took.
才能让上帝履行一点职责
To get God to work a rope line.
他厌恶这一切
He hated it.
人类意识到了这一点
And you know human sense that.
所以他们更加虔诚地祈祷
So they prayed harder and longer.
以他的名义发动无数战争
And fought more wars in his name.
都为了什么
And for what.
为了感染疟疾或者白血病而死吗
So they could die of malaria,leukemia.
终究只是责怪他们自己
And all the while,blaming themselves.
哦天啊 我要是更虔诚一点就不会这样了
Oh,If only I'd been more prayerful.
上帝就会爱我
God would have loved me.
上帝就会拯救我
God would have saved me.
事实是 上帝连他们的名字都不知道
You know what?God didn't even know their name.
但我知道
But I do.
因为我行于人间
Because,I walked among them.
我能拯救他们
And I can save them.
是的 你能
Sure,you can.
只要你的大脸出现在每一本圣经上
So long as you mug is in every Bible.
所有保险杠上都写着
And what would.
相信Metatron会怎么做
Metatron do is on every bumper.
怎么
And.
你是在责怪我给了他们所向往的一切吗
What,are you blaming me for giving them what they want.
给与他们一个信仰吗
Giving them a brand they can believe in.
我在责怪你杀了 Kevin
I'm blaming you for Kevin.
我在责怪你拿走了Cass的荣光
I'm blaming you for taking Cass's grace.
那么多废话 我当然在责怪你
Hell,I'm blaming you.
让芝加哥小熊队在过去一百年
For the cubs not winning the world series.
都没拿到世界职业棒球大赛的冠军
In the last 100 freaking years.
无论如何
Whatever it is.
都是你的错
I'm blaming you.
初刃
The first blade.
真是个麻烦的东西 不是吗
Nasty piece of work,isn't she.
好吧 Dean 假设你赢了
Okay,let's say you win,Dean.
然后我死了
And I die.
那接下来的世界会变得怎样呢
What's the world left with then.
一群娘娘腔天使还有你
A herd of panty-waisted angels and you.
你疯了吗
Are you out of you mind.
天知道你现在血管里流得是什么
With lord knows what pumping through those veins.
你刚才说的我只听到了一句话
You see,the only thing you said that went into my ear.
就是你会死
Was that you die.
好吧 来决斗吧
Fine,we'll fight.
我不知道你还有什么期盼
I don't know what you expect.
有谁会来帮你
Is gonna come of all this.
除非这就是你拖延时间的原因
Unless that's why you are stalling.
因为你知道
Because you know.
没有人会来了
Nothing is gonna come of this.
除非你的同伙成功进到天堂
Unless your pals succeed upstairs.
告诉你个新消息吧
Well here's a news flash.
你那两个矮胖子
Humpty and Dumpty.
现在正在主演
Are staring in their very own version.
天堂版本的异乡历劫呢
Of locked up abroad heaven right now.
那个从原始部落里拿来的蠢刀片
That big blade that douchy tribal tat.
真的给了你不少力量啊
Sure gave you some super juice.
放马来吧
Okay.
东西在哪
Where is it.
把她带下去
Remove her.
你以为搞定了Abbadon
So you took Abbadon's scalp.
然后就可以对付得了我这个无用的小老头了是吗
Then you figured you take on litte old nebbishy me.
到底是哪儿出了差错
What could go wrong.
你有那个蠢货的骨头提供能量
And you're powered by the bone of jackass.
让你觉得很厉害 是吧
And it is just awesome,right.
听着
Here's the deal.
下一次
Next time.
试试用上帝之言的力量
Try to be powered by the word of God.
退后
Stay back.
Metatron在哪
Where's Metatron.
不
No.
嘿 看着我Dean
Hey hey hey hey.
这招妙啊 Castiel
Well played Castiel.
显然你和Gadreel
Obviously you and Gadreel managed to.
想了一些办法来逼我到死路
Turn a few dead ends against me.
Gadreel死了
Gadreel is dead.
这么说Gardreel不在了
So Gadreel bites the dust.
而天使预言石
And the angel tablet.
宇宙中有史以来最强大的工具
Arguably the most powerful instrument.
变成碎片了
In the history of the universes is in pieces.
都是为了什么来着
And what again.
对了
Oh that's right.
为了救Dean Winchester
To save Dean Winchester.
这才是你的目的 对吧
And there was your goal,right.
我想你虽然打着天堂的旗号
I mean you draped yourself in the flag of heaven.
这最终都只是为了救那一个人类 是吧
But ultimately it was all about saving one human right.
你猜怎么着
Well,guess what.
他也死了
He's dead,too.
而你竟敢坐在我的椅子上
And you're sitting in my chair.
Sammy你得在他离回来之前赶紧离开这
Sammy you gotta get out of here before he comes back.
别说话
Shut up.
先用手按住这里
Just save your energy,alright.
我们会止住血的 我们会找个医生
We'll stop bleeding and we'll go to the doctor.
或者我们能找到咒语治好你的 你会好起来的
Or we'll find a spell.You're gonna be ok.
听我说
Listen to me.
这样反而更好
It's better this way.
什么
What.
该隐之印
The mark.
正在把我转变成不好的东西 我也不想
It's making me into something I don't wanna be.
别管什么该隐之印了
Don't worry about the mark.
等会儿再解决那个问题 你要坚持住 好吗
We'll figure out the mark later,just hold on,OK.
靠我身上
Give me some help.
你不可能成功脱身的
You will never get away with this.
从什么里脱身
Get away with what.
你给那帮没脑子的天使
You told a silly story.
随便编了个故事
To a group of less than believers.
我1个小时之内就能扭转回来
I'll clean up your mess in an hour.
你太不看重我们的兄弟姐妹了
You gave our brothers and sisters far too little credit.
他们很快就会发现 你一直在骗他们
They'll soon learnt that you've been,playing them.
然后呢
And then.
他们什么都不会做
They will do nothing.
因为他们就是一群吓坏了的小绵羊
Because they are frightened little sheep.
盲目地朝我手指的方向乱跑
Following my crook wherever it leads.
而我将要带领他们
And where I'm taking them.
回到我们的家园 远离这里的一切
Back to our rightful place atop this mountain of.
远离人类 羞耻 渣滓 等到那时
Human,shame and excrement.When that happens.
相信我 他们不会介意过程是怎样的
Trust me.They're not gonna care how they got there.
你之前不是说见死不救吗
What happen with you being okay with this.
我骗你的
I lied.
你个小混蛋
Ain't that a bitch.
你想过吗
You know.
为什么你一直无法身居高位掌握大权
Why you could never quite pull it together,Castiel.
为什么你现在又只能坐在这儿
Why you're sitting here with your.
感受着身体里的荣光一点点燃尽
Grace slowly burning away.
你的名声一直无法维持起来
And your reputation long extinguished.
你从来就不好奇
No curiosity.
你书读的不够多
You didn't read enough.
从来没学过 如果讲好一个故事
You never learnt how to tell a good story.
但是你可以
But you did.
抓住他
Take him.
Sam,等一下 等一下
Sam hold up,hold up.
我有话对你说
I gonna say something to you.
什么
What.
我真为我们骄傲
I'm proud of us.
不不不不不 嘿 嘿 醒醒 兄弟
No,no,hey,hey,wake up,buddy.
嘿
Hey.
Dean
Dean.
你做得对
You're doing the right thing.
留他一命
Letting him live.
这是领导者的风范
It's what a leader would do.
我不是什么领导者 Hannah
I'm not a leader,Hannah.
从来都不是
I never was.
我只想做个天使
I just wanna be an angel.
那你的荣光呢
And your grace.
你会怎么做
What will you do about that.
不继续补充荣光 你会死的
You will die if you don't replenish it.
该死的 Crowley
Damn it,Crowley.
是你把他拖下水
You got him into this mess.
你必须把他救回来
You will get him out.
我发誓
Or so help me god.
你弟弟
Your brother.
上帝保佑
Bless his soul.
我说话这会儿 他正在召唤我
Is summoning me as I speak.
做交易换回你
Make a deal,bring you back.
跟我之前说得一模一样 对吧
It's exactly what I was talking about,isn't it.
一切的一切
It's all become so.
又归在意料之中
Expected.
你要相信我
You have to believe me.
当我怂恿你继承该隐之印的时候
When I suggested you take on the Mark of Cain.
我并不知道事情会发展到这个地步
I didn't know this was going to happen.
我也没想到
Not really.
我可能没有告诉你故事的全部真相
I mean I might not have told you the entire truth.
但是我从没说过谎
But I never lied.
我从没说谎 Dean
I never lied,Dean.
这一点很重要
That's important.
是最主要的一点
It's fundamental.
但是
But.
还有一则关于Cain的故事
There's one story about Cain.
我可能
That I might have.
忘了告诉你
Forgotten to tell you.
很显然 他也想自行了断
Apparently,he,too,was willing to accept death.
而不是变成嗜血的杀手
Rather than becoming the killer.
就像印记想让他变成的那样
The Mark wanted him to be.
所以他用初刃了结了自己的生命
So he took his own life with the blade.
他死了
He died.
但是
Except.
就像传说里那样
As rumor has it.
该隐之印不是那么容易摆脱的
The Mark never quite let go.
你应该可以理解
You can understand.
我为什么没有告诉你这一点
Why I never spoke of this.
本来也只是一个推测 何必让人重拾希翼
Why set hearts aflutter at mere speculation.
你召唤我的时候 我还没有意识到
It wasn't until you summoned me.
没有
No.
直到你在餐馆点了芝士汉堡
It wasn't truly till you leave that cheeseburger.
却没有吃
Uneaten.
我才开始让自己
That I begun to let myself.
相信
Believe.
也许真的会有奇迹
Maybe miracles do come true.
听好了 Dean Winchester
Listen to me,Dean Winchester.
你现在经历的
What you're feeling right now.
不是死亡
It's not death.
而是新生
It's life.
一种全新的生活
A new kind of life.
睁开你的眼睛 Dean
Open your eyes,Dean.
观我所望
See what I see.
触我所感
Feel what I feel.
让我们一起对月长啸吧
Let's go take a howl at that moon.